# Michal Nawrocki

Fiolkowa 35, Gliwice 44-109, Silesia, Poland +48 571 447 422

michal.m.nawrocki@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/michal-m-nawrocki github.com/michal-nawrocki www.nawrocki.dev

### **Profile**

Recent Computer Science graduate with +2 years of commercial software development experience. Has a big understanding of software development and a passion for self-improvement. Is ready to tackle any problem and continue his self-taught programming journey. Interested in remote offers for engaging and exciting projects.

## Skills

- Fast learner
- Responsible
- Fluent in Polish, English, German
- Good with managing time
- Open to new experiences
- Creative
- Great with working in teams
- Reliable

### References

John Morris

Simulation Lead Developer Yobota, London, UK john@yobota.xyz

### **Interests**



Gaming



Synthwave Music



Reading



Foreign Languages



Sci-Fi Movies



Cooking



Playing the Guitar

## Technical skills

Languages Tools/Platforms Frameworks

Python, JS, TS, Java, JetBrains, VS Code, Git, Django, DRF, React, SQL, C#, C/C++, Haskell, Docker, Jenkins, Redis, FastAPI, Flutter

# Main areas of experience

• Object-oriented programming

Software engineering

PostgreSQL, AWS

• Test-driven development

REST APIsAlgorithms

Data Structures

HTML/CSS, Rust

Microservices

Web services

### Education

MSci Computer Science with an Industrial Year // 2016 - 2021 University of Birmingham, UK

Upper Second-Class Honours (2:1, 3.75 GPA)

Master's Project: Implementing a password manager product that uses voice authentication (Written in Python and Flutter)

Noticeable modules: Operating Systems, Networks, Network Security, Mobile computing with Android, Security of Real-World Systems, Algorithms and Complexity, Intelligent Robotics, Functional Programming

International Baccalaureate Diploma Programme // 2013 - 2016 Zespol Szkol Ogolnokstalcacy nr 10 in Gliwice, Poland

Final Mark - 35 out of 45

Noticeable subjects (out of 7): Computer Science HL (6), Mathematics (5)

# Work experience

Software Developer // September 2020 - Current Yobota, London, UK (remote work)

#### Responsibilities/Tasks/Duties:

- Took part in different projects and PODs (i.e. staff API)
- Improved and expanded Django REST Framework based services with new features and endpoints
- Maintained and refactored multiple repos across the organisation
- Took part in platform design discussions
- Co-wrote multiple microservices for the company's banking platform

Industrial placement // July 2019 - September 2020 Yobota, London, UK

### Responsibilities/Tasks/Duties:

- Expanded features of the company's simulation framework used to predict the behaviour of the in-house banking platform
- Containerized services using Heroku, AWS, Docker and Ansible
- Wrote Confluence documentation of the codebase
- Fixed bugs in the banking platform's staff app
- Made Jenkins pipelines. Automated tasks of the simulator

Game development group project // Spring 2018 University of Birmingham, UK

### Responsibilities/Tasks/Duties:

- Created a **UDP client-server** infrastructure for a **Java** based air traffic control simulator computer game
- Refactored and optimised game logic code to allow for multiplayer mode
- Collaborated on the renderer section of the game engine using OpenGL
- Documented and demonstrated the software to a publisher.